# **GERALD BARTLETT**

Languages: Python, JavaScript & Java. Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Web API (Rest), React Js, Node Js, Node ejs, UI/UX Design using Figma, Lucid Chart & Safe Agile using Trello Boards. Content Management using GitHub. Software Testing using J Unit. Database programming using PostgreSQL, Mongo db & MySql. Development tools such as Postman & Docker. I am passionate and focused when I take on any task. I am eager to learn, work well within a team and love eureka moments when coding.

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

## Highlights of Qualifications

- \* Software Development Diploma from Keyin College.
- \* In-class projects such as a python programs, webpage development using Html, JavaScript, React Js, Node Js, Node ejs.
- \*Worked well within multiple team settings.

  Recently part of a 3-person team that built 2 databases, 1 in PostgreSQL and 1 in Mongo DB with a frontend built in Node ejs using mock data from the Mockaroo website. This project required the search of a database that would print the results to the console as well as a localhost webpage, there would also be a log file created for user login

#### Contact

- gerald.bartlett@keyin.com
  gerald.bartlett@hotmail.com
  https://github.com/Gerald-Bartlett
  www.linkedin.com/in/gerald-bartlett0a93b7152
- (709) 571-1732
- New World Island, NL, A0g1P0

#### Education/Professional Development

- Software Development Diploma Program at Keyin College (Expected graduation Aug 2022)
- Certificate of Achievement My Finances 101 Keyin College 2021
- Learning Skills, a micro credential 2021
- Java boot Camp with Udemy 2022

Education/Professional Development

#### Education/Professional Development

- Construction Electrician Diploma from Die Trac Tech College
- St. Johns Ambulance First aid 2010
- MCSE with A+ 1998 (Microsoft certified systems engineer) WinNet Systems Ltd

Education/Professional Developmen

## Experience

May 2020 – Present

and search.

**Role**: Team Python Projects Keyin College, St. Johns/NL Created python programs for customer receipts, and a python program using Ariel and four-wheel wireless "robot" vehicles \*Successful implementation – Instructor Approved

**Role**: Team "Refrigerator" App Keyin College, St. Johns/NL Built web page using React Js, HTML & CSS which tract products in a refrigerator \*Instructor Approved

**Role**: Finals: Team Project 3-person team Date April 2022 – Present Keyin College, St. John's/NL built 2 databases, 1 in PostgreSQL and 1 in Mongo DB then we built a program called "Census" in Node ejs using mock data from the Mockaroo website. In this project we would have to search for specific data and in would print to the console as well as a web-page. It would also create a log file for user login and each search would also create a log event. All committed to GitHub repo. Grade receieved 91/100

**Role**: Finals: Team Project 3- person team Keyin College, St. Johns/NL built a search UI, Front End in React js. And Back End in Java, to search MSQL database tables. Development tools: Postman UI, MySQL UI. Then deployed to AWS & AWS S3 bucket via Docker Container. All committed to GitHub repo.

September 2012 – December 2020

**APPRENTICE ELECTRICIAN** *Culls Electrical, Horwood NL.* Worked closely with Clients on a daily basis covering plan design and changes to the electrical drawings. Coached and trained several apprentice electricians.

Mar 2011 - Aug 2011 APPRENTICE ELECTRICIAN Jenco Ltd, Twillingate, NL

Apr 2007 - Aug 2007 COMPUTER SUPPORT & ASSISTANT CLERK Breakwater Fisheries Ltd, Cottlesville,

NL Maintained company computers and network also as a Clerk, filing reports and

data entry from the company product suppliers

Dec 1995 - Jul 2001 SALES AGENT

Specialty Periodical Sales, Scarborough, Ont.- Customer Service, Sales, Delivery & marketing.

Jun 1991 - Jul 1995 SUPERVISOR Specialty Periodical Sales Ltd, Scarborough, Ont: Supervised up to 11

employees in a warehouse packaging & assembley line also maintained time sheets

and hourly rate of pay.

## Summary – Defining Qualities

Above are a list of my skills, work history & education here is a Summary of those skills, and qualities.

- Will always work hard at whatever I do. I may not be the best coder (at the moment) but I can honestly say No one will ever out work me. My work ethic says I have to do at least my share, it's who I am.
- Always make time to help my team / classmates in any situation.
- Excited to learn anything in IT such as new computer languages, libraries or frameworks.
- Quiet at times because I believe it's better to be slow to speak and quick to listen.
- Enjoy helping others whether it's a neighbor, friend or a complete stranger. Giving a Helping hand with things like an electrical issue, a plumbing issue or my favorite, helping students apply for college or university, & with applications for student loans, or funding through Service Canada programs. In my experience most never knew how to start the process.
- Tutored many in math and science, (I'm not a genius by the way lol). I also help low-income families file their personal income tax each year.
- "KPM tutor" (Keyin peer mentor) at Keyin College. A program that assist's high school students with learning Python language.